JAMES WOLFE

Email: Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com

Phone: 703)789-0919 Northern Virginia Website Portfolio

SUMMARY

Hardworking computer scientist with computer troubleshooting, programming, and customer service experience. I love to learn and problem-solve. I'm a highly self-motivated person who has produced several projects in the Cloud and on computer hardware. Utilizing skills in Linux, web design, and computer troubleshooting. I believe these are the skills that will allow me to thrive in a professional work environment.

SKILLS

- Software Troubleshooting
- Hardware Troubleshooting
- Linux

Project Management

- Website Design
- Software Development
- Cloud Configuration
- Cloud Security

PROJECTS

Website Financial Dashboard with Arrays GitHub Repository

- Devised an EC2 static website and implemented ApexCharts with Java arrays to store and propagate data into the financial dashboard.
- Used technical skills to develop the project for example, devised Java arrays for the bar and line chart quarters, launched a Linux OS EC2 server on AWS, and synchronized my local files with the EC2 instance through WinSCP.

Cloud Website Portfolios GitHub Repository

- Two static website portfolios involving the AWS Cloud service S3, IAM roles, and Azure's storage container service.
- Developed the websites utilizing HTML and CSS and used the project management tool Trello.

Established Computer System

- Strategized and executed a computer system and debugged boot and storage issues.
- Showed my skills reseating CMOS and accurately aligning memory when the system did not POST.

Headless Media Center

Achieved assembling a media center using a Raspberry Pi 4 by mounting OS to the device using Linux commands to login and create a
connection.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Woodworker Sue's Antiques

06/2021 — Present

Planned refurbishing projects for 18th and 19th century antique furniture involving sanding and staining utilizing attention to detail.

Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

11/2020 - 12/2020

- Accomplished hardware-focused AWS Cloud troubleshooting tickets involving unable to POST and vital updates.
- Adapted problem-solving skills to debug malfunctioning servers by rebooting servers or reseating, replacing server hardware, and CAT5/6 cables.

Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

06/2018 — 01/2019

Served customers while multi-tasking food orders, drink and chip refills, and station clean-up in a fast-paced environment.

Sale's Associate PetValu

09/2015 - 08/2017

• Faced with pet nutritional and health related issues I asked questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve customer concern and did it effectively by utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College 2016 — 2020